export const class10AIQuizData = {
                      //Communication Skills
  com_skill: [
    { question: "The communication which helps to understand others' thoughts and feelings",
      options: ["Non-verbal communication", "Verbal-communication", "Visual Communication", "Written communication"],
      answer: "Verbal-communication",
    },
    { question: "What is the main purpose of communication?",
      options: ["To impress others", "To share information and ideas", "To argue and win debates", "To show superiority"],
      answer: "To share information and ideas",
    },
    { question: "Which of the following is an example of non-verbal communication?",
      options: ["Writing an email", "Talking on the phone", "Smiling at someone", "Sending a text message"],
      answer: "Smiling at someone",
    },
    { question: "What is the correct order of the communication process?",
      options: ["Sender → Message → Receiver → Feedback", "Message → Sender → Receiver → Feedback", "Receiver → Message → Sender → Feedback", "Feedback → Message → Sender → Receiver"],
      answer: "Sender → Message → Receiver → Feedback",
    },
    { question: "Which of the following is a good example of active listening?",
      options: ["Interrupting the speaker to share your own thoughts", "Looking at your phone while someone talks", "Nodding and asking relevant questions", "Ignoring what’s being said"],
      answer: "Nodding and asking relevant questions",
    },
    { question: "Which of these is not a barrier to effective communication?",
      options: ["Noise", "Active listening", "Language differences", "Emotional disturbance"],
      answer: "Active listening",
    },
    
  ],
                      //Self Management Skill
  self_mgmt_skill: [
    { question: "Which of the following is the best example of self-management?",
      options: ["Waiting for someone to remind you about your homework", "Planning your day and finishing your tasks on time", "Ignoring your responsibilities", "Blaming others for your mistakes"],
      answer: "Planning your day and finishing your tasks on time",
    },
    { question: "Which of the following is not a part of self-awareness?",
      options: ["Knowing your strengths", "Understanding your weaknesses", "Comparing yourself constantly with others", "Recognizing your emotions"],
      answer: "Comparing yourself constantly with others",
    },
    { question: "What is the first step in setting personal goals?",
      options: ["Writing down rewards", "Asking friends for suggestions", "Understanding your interests and abilities", "Waiting for opportunities"],
      answer: "Understanding your interests and abilities",
    },
    { question: "Stress management techniques include all of the following except:",
      options: ["Deep breathing and meditation", "Positive thinking", "Time management", "Procrastination"],
      answer: "Procrastination",
    },
    { question: "Which statement defines self-motivation the best?",
      options: ["Getting motivated only when praised by others", "Pushing yourself to achieve goals without external pressure", "Depending on others for reminders", "Waiting for the right time to act"],
      answer: "Pushing yourself to achieve goals without external pressure",
    },
    
  ],
                //ICT Skills
  ict_skill: [
    { question: "ICT stands for ?",
      options: ["Information and Computer Technology", "Internet and Communication Technique", "Information and Communication Technology", "Internet and Computer Technology"],
      answer: "Information and Communication Technology",
    },
    { question: "Which of the following is NOT an example of an ICT tool?",
      options: ["Smartphone", "Internet browser", "Calculator", "File folder"],
      answer: "File folder",
    },
    { question: "Which of the following devices is used to convert printed text into a digital format?",
      options: ["Printer", "Scanner", "Speaker", "Projector"],
      answer: "Scanner",
    },
    { question: "Which software is used for creating presentations?",
      options: ["MS Word", "MS Excel", "MS PowerPoint", "MS Access"],
      answer: "MS PowerPoint",
    },
    { question: "What is the shortcut key to copy selected text in most applications?",
      options: ["Ctrl + V", "Ctrl + C", "Ctrl + X", "Ctrl + A"],
      answer: "Ctrl + C",
    },
    { question: "Which of the following represents input in an ICT system?",
      options: ["Report printed on paper", "Data entered using a keyboard", "Output displayed on screen", "Processed information stored in a file"],
      answer: "Data entered using a keyboard",
    },
    { question: "Which of the following is the correct sequence of data processing in ICT?",
      options: ["Input → Output → Process", "Output → Input → Process", "Input → Process → Output", "Process → Output → Input"],
      answer: "Input → Process → Output",
    },
    { question: "What is the main purpose of using cloud storage?",
      options: ["To store data only on local drives", "To share large files offline", "To access data from anywhere with internet", "To delete old files automatically"],
      answer: "To access data from anywhere with internet",
    },
    { question: "Which of the following practices helps ensure cyber safety while using ICT tools?",
      options: ["Sharing passwords with friends", "Clicking unknown links from emails", "Installing antivirus software", "Using public Wi-Fi for banking"],
      answer: "Installing antivirus software",
    },
    { question: "Which of the following is an example of a communication service in ICT?",
      options: ["Google Drive", "MS Word", "Paint", "Gmail"],
      answer: "Gmail",
    },
    
  ],
                  //Entrepreneurial Skill
  entre_skill: [
    { question: "Who is an entrepreneur?",
      options: ["A person who starts and runs their own business", "A person who manages someone else’s company", "A person who avoids taking risks", "A person who works only for others"],
      answer: "A person who starts and runs their own business",
    },
    { question: "Which of the following is not a quality of a good entrepreneur?",
      options: ["Creativity", "Self-confidence", "Laziness", "Risk-taking ability"],
      answer: "Laziness",
    },
    { question: "Which of the following best describes “innovation”?",
      options: ["Copying someone else’s product", "Improving or creating something new", "Sticking to old ideas", "Avoiding changes in business"],
      answer: "Improving or creating something new",
    },
    { question: "Which of these is an example of an entrepreneurial activity?",
      options: ["Starting a small online bakery", "Working as an employee in a factory", "Following a routine job without change", "Waiting for a government job"],
      answer: "Starting a small online bakery",
    },
    { question: "Which of the following is a major risk in entrepreneurship?",
      options: ["Chance of failure or loss", "Getting too many customers", "Working without goals", "Making too much profit"],
      answer: "Chance of failure or loss",
    },
    
  ],
                  //Green Skill
  green_skill: [
    { question: "What do Green Skills mainly focus on?",
      options: ["Increasing industrial production", "Protecting the environment and using resources sustainably", "Promoting plastic use for convenience", "Reducing employment opportunities"],
      answer: "Protecting the environment and using resources sustainably",
    },
    { question: "Which of the following is a renewable source of energy?",
      options: ["Coal", "Petroleum", "Solar energy", "Natural gas"],
      answer: "Solar Energy",
    },
    { question: "Which of these actions best represents sustainable development?",
      options: ["Using resources without worrying about future generations", "Recycling waste materials to reduce pollution", "Cutting down forests for more buildings", "Increasing vehicle usage for comfort"],
      answer: "Recycling waste materials to reduce pollution",
    },
    { question: "What does the term “Green Economy” mean?",
      options: ["An economy that focuses on profit only", "An economy that ignores environmental issues", "An economy that balances growth with environmental care", "An economy that depends completely on fossil fuels"],
      answer: "An economy that balances growth with environmental care",
    },
    { question: "Which of the following is not a Green Skill?",
      options: ["Waste management", "Energy conservation", "Eco-friendly design", "Excessive paper usage"],
      answer: "Excessive paper usage",
    },
    
  ],
                    //Introduction to AI
  intro_to_AI: [
    { question: "What does AI stand for?",
      options: ["Automated Internet", "Artificial Intelligence", "Advanced Information", "Automatic Integration"],
      answer: "Artificial Intelligence",
    },
    { question: "Which of the following best defines Artificial Intelligence?",
      options: ["Machines that can think and perform tasks like humans", "Computers that store large amounts of data only", "Internet-based software programs", "Any automated machine without intelligence"],
      answer: "Machines that can think and perform tasks like humans",
    },
    { question: "Which of the following is an example of AI in daily life?",
      options: ["Online banking using OTP", "Self-driving cars", "Using a calculator", "Writing notes by hand"],
      answer: "Self-driving cars",
    },
    { question: "AI can be classified into which two main types?",
      options: ["Supervised and Unsupervised", "Weak AI and Strong AI", "Machine Learning and Deep Learning", "Natural and Artificial"],
      answer: "Weak AI and Strong AI",
    },
    { question: "Which of these is a major benefit of AI?",
      options: ["Reduces repetitive human tasks", "Causes only unemployment", "Works slower than humans", "Eliminates the need for machines"],
      answer: "Reduces repetitive human tasks",
    },
    
  ],
}
